const quizQuestions16en = [{
    question:"The inductance of the arc welding circuit:",
    answers: ["provides extra energy to the arc after a short circuit has ended (after the metal droplet has been transferred by the short circuit mechanism);",
    "limits the maximum short-circuit current value in cases of sticking the electrode to the weld pool;",
    "limits the maximum value of arc voltage after a short circuit ends (after the transfer of a metal droplet by the short circuit mechanism);",
    "increases the thermal efficiency of the welding arc."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The inductance of the arc welding circuit:",
    answers: ["limits the maximum short-circuit current value in cases of sticking the electrode to the weld pool;",
    "assists arc re-ignition after polarity change in alternating current welding;",
    "limits the maximum value of arc voltage after a short circuit ends (after the transfer of a metal droplet by the short circuit mechanism);",
    "increases the thermal efficiency of the welding arc."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The inductance of the arc welding circuit:",
    answers: ["limits the maximum short-circuit current value in cases of sticking the electrode to the weld pool;",
    "limits the maximum value of arc voltage after a short circuit ends (after the transfer of a metal droplet by the short circuit mechanism);",
    "increases the thermal efficiency of the welding arc;",
    "can reduce or increase (depending on its value) spatter generation."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the role of the inductance of the welding circuit, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["Inductance regulation is more important in the case of MIG/MAG welding with spray transfer than in the case of MIG/MAG welding with short circuits transfer mode.",
    "It can limit the maximum value that the short-circuit current would reach during short-circuits, thus reducing the generation of spatter from explosions of metal bridges.",
    "When the inductance is lower, the stability of the welding process is better and less spatter is generated.",
    "When the inductance is higher, the stability of the welding process is better and less spatter is generated."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the role of the inductance of the welding circuit, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The inductance should always be kept as low as possible to reduce spatter generation.",
    "The main objective of the inductance (mainly in GMAW) is to control the rising and falling rates of current and, therefore, decreasing the spatter generation and ensuring the stability of the process.",
    "The inductance should always be kept as high as possible to improve the stability of the welding process.",
    "Inductance regulation is more important in the case of MIG/MAG welding with spray transfer than in the case of MIG/MAG welding with short circuits transfer mode."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the role of the inductance of the welding circuit, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The inductance should always be kept as low as possible to reduce spatter generation.",
    "The inductance should always be kept as high as possible to improve the stability of the welding process.",
    "The increase in inductance can either improve or impair the performance of the welding process, since for each welding condition with metal transfer there will be an optimal value of inductance.",
    "Inductance regulation is more important in the case of MIG/MAG welding with spray transfer than in the case of MIG/MAG welding with short circuits transfer mode."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the role of the inductance of the welding circuit, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The inductance should always be kept as low as possible to reduce spatter generation.",
    "The inductance is responsible for the arc active resistance, so the higher the inductance, the more heat is generated.",
    "The main objective of the inductance (mainly in GTAW/TIG) is to control the rising and falling rates of current and, therefore, decreasing the spatter generation and ensuring the stability of the process.",
    "Inductance regulation is more important in the case of MIG/MAG welding with short circuits transfer mode than in the case of MIG/MAG welding with spray transfer."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The inductance of the arc welding circuit:",
    answers: ["affects the behavior of the current, mainly in the case of a short-circuit metal transfer mode;",
    "cannot be changed on purpose (by equipment adjustment);",
    "has the function of keeping the arc voltage constant;",
    "has the function of ensuring the Constant Current type of the power source static characteristic, since its main function is to maintain the current at the same level."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The inductance of the arc welding circuit:",
    answers: ["cannot be changed on purpose (by equipment adjustment);",
    "is controlled by a source component, called an inductor (in electromagnetic sources), installed in series with the secondary circuit, which is a part of the welding circuit.",
    "has the function of keeping the arc voltage constant;",
    "has the function of ensuring the Constant Current type of the power source static characteristic, since its main function is to maintain the current at the same level."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The inductance of the arc welding circuit:",
    answers: ["cannot be changed on purpose (by equipment adjustment);",
    "has the function of keeping the arc voltage constant;",
    "can limit the maximum value the current that would be reached during short circuits;",
    "has the function of ensuring the Constant Current type of the power source static characteristic, since its main function is to maintain the current at the same level."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Comparing the electroslag (ESW) and electrogas (EGW) processes, it is possible to state that:",
    answers: ["only the electroslag process generates large columnar grains and extensive HAZ, as the energy is less concentrated;",
    "the electroslag process requires gas to protect the slag against atmospheric oxidation;",
    "there is no arc during the operation of the ESW process, while the EGW process is an arc welding process;",
    "the ESW process can only be used in the flat position, while the EGW process can be applied in any welding position."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the shielding gas in aluminium TIG welding, indicate the correct statement.",
    answers: ["Oxidizing mixtures are not used to avoid excessive oxidation of the weld pool.",
    "In thick plate welding, helium can be added to argon when an increase in molten metal area is desired.",
    "Although helium is a more expensive gas than argon, its use instead of argon is justifiable, as it offers more efficient protection, which allows to drastically reduce the flow rates used.",
    "Ar-H2 mixtures can be used if a better protection for the tungsten electrode is needed."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In MIG/MAG welding with alternating current, the following characteristic stands out as true:",
    answers: ["The current level in the positive polarity is greater than that in the negative one to maintain the same melting rate in both polarities and thus keep the arc length constant during polarity reversals.",
    "The current level in the positive polarity is smaller than in the negative one to maintain the same melting rate in both polarities and thus keep the arc length constant during polarity reversals.",
    "The stability of the alternating current arc is low; therefore, this process is used only in maintenance.",
    "Process of a very high deposition rate (compatible with the Double Wire MIG), due to the negative polarity contribution."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the statements listed below is correct regarding thermal spraying?",
    answers: ["The adhesion strength is very high.",
    "Surface pre-treatment, e.g., blasting, is necessary to obtain an adequate bonding of coatings.",
    "Thermal spray coatings are non-porous.",
    "Plasma spray coatings have poorer bonding and lower density compared to flame spray."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the statements listed below is correct regarding thermal spraying?",
    answers: ["The adhesion strength is very high.",
    "Generally, a surface pre-treatment is not necessary to obtain a good bonding of the coatings.",
    "Thermal spray coatings are non-porous.",
    "Plasma spray coatings have a better bonding and a higher density compared to flame spray."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding coatings, it is possible to say that:",
    answers: ["Surface treatments differ from coatings in that surface treatments add little or no mass to the surface.",
    "Thermally sprayed coatings never receive post-spray treatments.",
    "In thermal spraying, substrate preparation (surface cleaning) is basically done by cathodic cleaning.",
    "Coatings and surface treatments are names of the same technological process (i.e. in this case they are synonymous)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding coatings, it is possible to say that:",
    answers: ["Thermally sprayed coatings never receive post-spray treatments.",
    "In thermal spraying, substrate preparation (surface cleaning) is basically done by cathodic cleaning.",
    "Thermal spraying is a group of processes in which metallic or non-metallic materials finely divided into droplets are deposited in a molten or semi-molten condition onto a substrate.",
    "Coatings and surface treatments are names of the same technological process (i.e. in this case they are synonymous)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following properties of a gas should be taken into account when selecting a plasma gas for PAW?",
    answers: ["Thermal conductivity.",
    "Boiling point (°C).",
    "Density.",
    "The ability to react with tungsten to increase the thermionic emission from the electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The degrees of freedom of a robot are (is):",
    answers: ["the number of the robot arm joints;",
    "the number of processes it can operate on;",
    "the angular movements that can be performed;",
    "the number of programs that can run in parallel."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following welding processes can operate the key-hole technique?",
    answers: [" TIG welding (GTAW).",
    "High current plasma welding with transferred arc.",
    "Plasma welding with non-transferred arc.",
    "A-TIG welding (A-GTAW)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following welding processes can operate the key-hole technique?",
    answers: [" TIG welding (GTAW).",
    "A-TIG welding (A-GTAW).",
    "Plasma welding with non-transferred arc.",
    "Electron Beam Welding (EBW)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of these processes is most suitable for making a 1 m high and 30 kg workpiece by additive manufacturing?",
    answers: [" TIG welding (GTAW).",
    "MIG/MAG welding (GMAW).",
    " Laser directed energy deposition (L-DED).",
    "Selective Laser Fusion."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Indicate the correct alternative in relation to the adjustment of a MIG/MAG process parameter, keeping the other parameters unchanged:",
    answers: ["If you increase the wire feed speed, the arc voltage will take on a slightly higher value.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, the arc length takes on a smaller and smaller value.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, the current also increases.",
    "As the distance from the contact tip to the workpiece increases, the penetration also increases."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the control of the deposition rate in MIG/MAG welding process it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["To increase the deposition rate, keeping the same current, it is necessary to increase the contact tip-to-work distance and, at the same time, the wire feed speed.",
    "To increase the deposition rate, keeping the same current, it is necessary to decrease the contact tip-to-work distance.",
    "To increase the deposition rate, keeping the same current, it is necessary to increase the arc voltage.",
    "There is no way to increase the deposition rate if the current must be kept constant (because it is exactly the current that is responsible for melting the electrode wire)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What fluxes should preferably be used in SAW process of structures that do not require high demands on the mechanical properties of the weld metal?",
    answers: ["Basic fluxes of the alumina-basic type.",
    "Calcium-silicate and aluminium-rutile neutral fluxes.",
    "Active and alloyed fluxes.",
    "Basic fluxes of the alumina-silica type."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What fluxes should preferably be used in SAW process of structures that do not require high demands on the mechanical properties of the weld metal?",
    answers: ["Basic fluxes of the alumina-basic type.",
    "Active and alloyed fluxes.",
    "Acid fluxes of the manganese-silicate type.",
    "Basic fluxes of the alumina-silica type."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding electrical resistance welding, it is possible to state that:",
    answers: ["The heat generation by the Joule effect along the thickness is minimal and there is no need to worry about this aspect.",
    "In projection welding with two points at once, there is no need to worry about the shunt effect.",
    "Seam welding is achieved by placing spaced lugs on the rotating electrode disc.",
    "When making a second weld point close to the one already made (in RSW), it is recommended to reduce the current by 10% as the joint already has a guaranteed mechanical strength."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding electrical resistance welding, it is possible to state that:",
    answers: ["The heat generation by the Joule effect along the thickness is minimal and there is no need to worry about this aspect.",
    "Seam welding is achieved by placing spaced lugs on the rotating electrode disc.",
    "When using RSW to weld points that are too close one to other, it may be necessary to use a higher value of current from the second spot.",
    "When making a second weld point close to the one already made (in RSW), it is recommended to reduce the current by 10% as the joint already has a guaranteed mechanical strength."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding electroslag welding (ESW), it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The arc is protected by a thick slag, ensuring that there is no porosity.",
    "There is no arc during operation.",
    "Welding in any position is possible as the flux is trapped between shoes.",
    "Contact tips must be located on top of the flux layer to prevent them from being fused."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding electroslag welding (ESW), it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The arc is protected by a thick slag, ensuring that there is no porosity.",
    "Welding in any position is possible as the flux is trapped between shoes.",
    "Contact tips must be located on top of the flux layer to prevent them from being fused.",
    "It produces a single bead in butt joints of plates positioned vertically, but with large granulometry from a metallurgical point of view."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What process is NOT used for deposition/application of coatings?",
    answers: ["Explosion welding.",
    "Electroerosion.",
    "Arc welding.",
    "Thermal Spraying."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding robots, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["An industrial robot consists of a mechanical arm composed of links, connected together by joints, whose number determines what is called Degrees of Freedom.",
    "The number of degrees of freedom of a robot is its number of links.",
    "The human arm has 6 degrees of freedom.",
    "In welding, robots ensure greater repeatability and they can compensate for some problems of a poorly made joint fit up."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding robots, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The number of degrees of freedom of a robot is its number of links.",
    "The greater is the number of degrees of freedom of a robot, the greater is its spatial mobility;",
    "The human arm has 6 degrees of freedom.",
    "In welding, robots ensure greater repeatability and they can compensate for some problems of a poorly made joint fit up."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding robots, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["The number of degrees of freedom of a robot is its number of links.",
    "The human arm has 6 degrees of freedom.",
    "Most industrial robots have between four and six degrees of freedom. Those used in welding generally have 6 degrees of freedom.",
    "In welding, robots ensure greater repeatability and they can compensate for some problems of a poorly made joint fit up."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is one of the advantages of MAG welding with industrial robots compared to semi-automatic MAG welding?",
    answers: ["Larger assembly tolerances of the parts to be welded can be accepted.",
    "Materials with low weldability can also be welded.",
    "Fewer imperfections in welding.",
    "Higher wire feed speeds may be applied."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is one of the advantages of MAG welding with industrial robots compared to semi-automatic MAG welding?",
    answers: ["Larger assembly tolerances of the parts to be welded can be accepted.",
    "Materials with low weldability can also be welded.",
    "Higher wire feed speeds may be applied.",
    "Reproducible weld quality."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is one of the advantages of MAG welding with industrial robots compared to semi-automatic MAG welding?",
    answers: ["Larger assembly tolerances of the parts to be welded can be accepted.",
    "Materials with low weldability can also be welded.",
    "Higher productivity.",
    "Higher wire feed speeds may be applied."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The presence of a small amount of O2 in the gas mixture used for MAG welding (GMAW) of austenitic stainless steel is:",
    answers: ["needed to reduce the heat input (via arc temperature reduction);",
    "necessary to reduce the surface tension of the material;",
    "necessary to prevent the absorption of H2;",
    "used to reduce the cost of gas as it makes it less pure."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the hot plate welding of plastics, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["Dissimilar materials (plastics) cannot be hot plate welded. ",
    "This method can provide a joint strength that is equal to that of the base material.",
    "In this process, the joint design is similar to that used in filler metal welding.",
    "In this welding method, the filler rod is applied only after the hot plate is removed."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the hot plate welding of plastics, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["Dissimilar materials (plastics) cannot be hot plate welded. ",
    "In this process, the joint design is similar to that used in filler metal welding.",
    "The hot plate is removed after the surfaces to be joined have been melted or softened.",
    "In this welding method, the filler rod is applied only after the hot plate is removed."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the hot plate welding of plastics, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["Dissimilar materials (plastics) cannot be hot plate welded. ",
    "In this process, the joint design is similar to that used in filler metal welding.",
    "In this welding method, the filler rod is applied only after the hot plate is removed.",
    "After removing the hot plate, the joint is consolidated and cooled under pressure."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Applicable processes for joining plastics are:",
    answers: ["Adhesive bonding, solvent welding, non-consumable electrode welding.",
    "Hot gas welding, adhesive bonding, electro-fusion welding.",
    "Adhesive bonding, solvent welding, electron beam welding.",
    "Electric resistance butt welding, solvent welding, non-consumable electrode welding."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Applicable processes for joining plastics are:",
    answers: ["Adhesive bonding, solvent welding, non-consumable electrode welding.",
    "Adhesive bonding, solvent welding, electron beam welding.",
    "Adhesive bonding, solvent welding, hot plate welding.",
    "Electric resistance butt welding, solvent welding, non-consumable electrode welding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Applicable processes for joining plastics are:",
    answers: ["Adhesive bonding, solvent welding, non-consumable electrode welding.",
    "Adhesive bonding, solvent welding, electron beam welding.",
    "Electric resistance butt welding, solvent welding, non-consumable electrode welding.",
    "Hot gas welding, friction welding, electro-fusion welding."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the true statement about metal transfer phenomenon in the MIG/MAG welding:",
    answers: ["Gravity forces always facilitate metal droplet transfer, regardless of the welding position.",
    "Within a small range of current (called transition current) a change in the droplet formation mode takes place, from large droplets at low frequency to small droplets at high frequency.",
    "Ar+CO2 mixtures rich in argon (above 90%) favour spray metal transfer, even with welding currents typical for short-circuiting metal transfer.",
    "The globular type transfer occurs mainly due to a lack of flow of shielding gas."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the true statement about metal transfer phenomenon in the MIG/MAG welding:",
    answers: ["Gravity forces always facilitate metal droplet transfer, regardless of the welding position.",
    "Ar+CO2 mixtures rich in argon (above 90%) favour spray metal transfer, even with welding currents typical for short-circuiting metal transfer.",
    "The value of the transition current (globular/spray transfer) depends on the shielding gas, the electrode material, the electrode diameter and its extension.",
    "The globular type transfer occurs mainly due to a lack of flow of shielding gas."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the true statement about metal transfer phenomenon in the MIG/MAG welding:",
    answers: ["Gravity forces always facilitate metal droplet transfer, regardless of the welding position.",
    "Ar+CO2 mixtures rich in argon (above 90%) favour spray metal transfer, even with welding currents typical for short-circuiting metal transfer.",
    "The globular type transfer occurs mainly due to a lack of flow of shielding gas.",
    "Generally speaking, the higher the current, the smaller the size of droplets in transfer."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"To increase the deposition rate in the MIG/MAG welding process, keeping the same average current, one must:",
    answers: ["increase the contact tip-to-work distance and, at the same time, the wire feed speed;",
    "increase the wire diameter;",
    "change the metal transfer from short-circuiting to spray by increasing the arc voltage.",
    "change direct current to pulsed current keeping the same wire feed speed."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A welding arc can be opened in different ways (from a non-conductive situation at room temperature) using the non-contact technique or contact ignition. Essential to all these techniques is that:",
    answers: ["the cathode is heated strongly until it begins to emit electrons by thermionic emission or field emission;",
    "the anode must always have a higher temperature than the cathode;",
    "the cathode must always have a higher temperature than the anode;",
    "the no-load voltage should be 2 - 4 times higher than the arc voltage value."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding explosion welding, the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["In this welding process, coalescence between the two metallic surfaces is quickly obtained by the energy of detonation, when one of the pieces is thrown towards the other by the explosion.",
    "There is a need to preheat the sheets, due to their large dimensions.",
    "The filler metal used works similarly to the case of brazing, wetting the joint interface.",
    "In this process the shielding gas is injected into the gap between the sheets to be joined."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding explosion welding, the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["There is a need to preheat the sheets, due to their large dimensions.",
    "No filler metal is used.",
    "The filler metal used works similarly to the case of brazing, wetting the joint interface.",
    "In this process the shielding gas is injected into the gap between the sheets to be joined."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding explosion welding, the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["There is a need to preheat the sheets, due to their large dimensions.",
    "The filler metal used works similarly to the case of brazing, wetting the joint interface.",
    "It is commonly used in joining two dissimilar metals, in particular, to “clade” a nobler metal over the base metal (substrate) over large areas.",
    "In this process the shielding gas is injected into the gap between the sheets to be joined."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding explosion welding, the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["There is a need to preheat the sheets, due to their large dimensions.",
    "The filler metal used works similarly to the case of brazing, wetting the joint interface.",
    "In this process the shielding gas is injected into the gap between the sheets to be joined.",
    "\"Bonding is generally achieved by mechanical interlocking resulting from undulations at the interface between the surfaces. "],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0"
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the properties of plastics, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["Thermoplastic polymers have an amorphous or semi-crystalline structure.",
    "The most welded polymers are the thermoset ones.",
    "They are less sensitive to temperature than metals.",
    "Their properties do not change over time."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the properties of plastics, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The most welded polymers are the thermoset ones.",
    "The amorphous structure makes the polymer exhibit greater impact strength, since the chains have free space in the bulk of the polymer to deform.",
    "They are less sensitive to temperature than metals.",
    "Their properties do not change over time."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the properties of plastics, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The most welded polymers are the thermoset ones.",
    "They are less sensitive to temperature than metals.",
    "Thermosets are infusible, that is, they cannot be remolded.",
    "Their properties do not change over time."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the properties of composites and the joining processes for them, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["Composites represent a combination of two or more components with superior properties compared to each component alone.",
    "Adhesive bonding is not applicable for composites, as they do not represent homogeneous materials.",
    "The most commonly used joining process is TIG welding.",
    "For the weld metal to have characteristics compatible with those of the base material, it is necessary to apply buttering to the surfaces to be joined."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"This is an advantage of thermal spraying compared to coating by welding:",
    answers: ["low porosity;",
    "high bond strength to the substrate;",
    "low dilution in the substrate;",
    "higher density of the deposited layer."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"This is an advantage of thermal spraying compared to coating by welding:",
    answers: ["low porosity;",
    "high bond strength to the substrate;",
    "higher density of the deposited layer;",
    "low thermal effects on the substrate."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When is it necessary to use sensors in the case of robotic arc welding?",
    answers: ["\"Sensors are always present in arc welding (e.g., arc voltage is a \"\"through-the-arc\"\" type sensor!)\"",
    "In the case of wide tolerances of the joint fit up.",
    "In the case of welding of responsible (critical) parts.",
    "When the robot is programmed offline."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"When is it necessary to use sensors in the case of robotic arc welding?",
    answers: ["\"Sensors are always present in arc welding (e.g., arc voltage is a \"\"through-the-arc\"\" type sensor!)\"",
    "In the case of welding of responsible (critical) parts.",
    "In case of an excessive distortion of the workpieces during the welding process.",
    "When the robot is programmed offline."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The level of weld quality assured by a robotic system depends on:",
    answers: ["robot repeatability;",
    "the method of programming, on-line or off-line;",
    "the chosen metal transfer mode (spray mode always leads to better quality);",
    "the welding process used."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The level of weld quality assured by a robotic system depends on:",
    answers: ["the method of programming, on-line or off-line;",
    "the adjustment of the welding process parameters;",
    "the chosen metal transfer mode (spray mode always leads to better quality);",
    "the welding process used."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The level of weld quality assured by a robotic system depends on:",
    answers: ["the method of programming, on-line or off-line;",
    "the chosen metal transfer mode (spray mode always leads to better quality);",
    "tolerances of the joint parts fit up;",
    "the welding process used."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The level of weld quality assured by a robotic system depends on:",
    answers: ["the method of programming, on-line or off-line;",
    "the chosen metal transfer mode (spray mode always leads to better quality);",
    "the welding process used;",
    "fixing accessories (jigs, fixtures, ...)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In thermal spraying, a good adhesion of the coatings is conditioned by:",
    answers: ["prior cleaning of the substrate surface;",
    "prior buttering of the substrate surface;",
    "greater difference between plasticity of the coating and the substrate;",
    "greater difference between the coefficient of linear expansion of the coating and the substrate."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In thermal spraying, a good adhesion of the coatings is conditioned by:",
    answers: ["prior buttering of the substrate surface;",
    "high surface roughness;",
    "greater difference between plasticity of the coating and the substrate;",
    "greater difference between the coefficient of linear expansion of the coating and the substrate."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of off-line robot programming:",
    answers: ["Due to the fact that the programmer moves the robot (which must be \"\"off-line\"\") manually along the weld to be performed, a high accuracy of the robot's subsequent performance is ensured.",
    "In general, the off-line programming system allows graphical simulation of movements, allowing to verify collisions between the torch and the workpieces.",
    "It is easier to learn and use than programming on-line.",
    "Less programming steps than with on-line (hand-guiding) programming."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of off-line robot programming:",
    answers: ["\"Due to the fact that the programmer moves the robot (which must be \"\"off-line\"\") manually along the weld to be performed, a high accuracy of the robot's subsequent performance is ensured.\"",
    "It is easier to learn and use than programming on-line.",
    "Possibility of integration with CAD/CAM system, allowing also a higher integration between the design and production phases.",
    "Less programming steps than with on-line (hand-guiding) programming."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of off-line robot programming:",
    answers: ["No need for the programmer to get in touch with the work environment.",
    "\"Due to the fact that the programmer moves the robot (which must be \"\"off-line\"\") manually along the weld to be performed, a high accuracy of the robot's subsequent performance is ensured.\"",
    "It is easier to learn and use than programming on-line.",
    "Less programming steps than with on-line (hand-guiding) programming."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the characteristics of off-line programming (or indirect programming) of robots, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["It consists of teaching the robot by guiding it through the desired trajectory by the user.",
    "\"Due to the fact that the programmer moves the robot (which must be \"\"off-line\"\") manually along the weld to be performed, a high accuracy of the robot's subsequent performance is ensured.\"",
    "This programming mode increases idle time: the robot cannot be kept on the production line while it is being programmed.",
    "After transferring the program to the robot controller, it is necessary to carry out a calibration between the model and the physical structure of the robot cell."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the characteristics of off-line programming (or indirect programming) of robots, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["It is done on a computer separate from the robot.",
    "It consists of teaching the robot by guiding it through the desired trajectory by the user.",
    "\"Due to the fact that the programmer moves the robot (which must be \"\"off-line\"\") manually along the weld to be performed, a high accuracy of the robot's subsequent performance is ensured.\"",
    "This programming mode increases idle time: the robot cannot be kept on the production line while it is being programmed."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the characteristics of off-line programming (or indirect programming) of robots, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["It consists of teaching the robot by guiding it through the desired trajectory by the user.",
    "It is a programming developed using a theoretical model of the robot and the work environment.",
    "\"Due to the fact that the programmer moves the robot (which must be \"\"off-line\"\") manually along the weld to be performed, a high accuracy of the robot's subsequent performance is ensured.\"",
    "This programming mode increases idle time: the robot cannot be kept on the production line while it is being programmed."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the characteristics of off-line programming (or indirect programming) of robots, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["It consists of teaching the robot by guiding it through the desired trajectory by the user.",
    "\"Due to the fact that the programmer moves the robot (which must be \"\"off-line\"\") manually along the weld to be performed, the high accuracy of the robot's subsequent performance is ensured.\"",
    "There is no need for the programmer to get in touch with the work environment (lower cost and greater agility to correct errors).",
    "This programming mode increases idle time: the robot cannot be kept on the production line while it is being programmed."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The main disadvantage of on-line robot programming is:",
    answers: ["Requires additional software and a computer.",
    "While performing this type of programming, the robot cannot be used to perform the welding, as the programmer moves the robot manually along the weld to be performed.",
    "The program must be supplemented later with welding parameters, movement speed, welding start and end, etc.",
    "This type of programming is very complicated and is rarely used in robotic welding."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the properties of the Heat Affected Zone (HAZ) in the welding of carbon steels by fusion it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["The HAZ is usually a region of high hardness and low toughness;",
    "The higher the heat input, the higher the cooling rate, resulting in harder metallurgical structures;",
    "The HAZ normalizing region of a carbon steel usually has a smaller grain size than that observed in the base metal;",
    "The maximum hardness of the HAZ depends solely on the chemical composition of the steel (hardenability)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The presence of hydrogen in argon + hydrogen gas mixtures used in TIG/GTAW welding of carbon steel can:",
    answers: ["cause embrittlement;",
    "increase oxidation;",
    "reduce porosity;",
    "increase porosity."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding low carbon steels with a high iron oxide content (semi-killed, rimmed steels):",
    answers: ["low hydrogen electrodes are recommended;",
    "impurities can cause weld defects;",
    "weld metal hardness can be very high;",
    "heat input should be low."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Sensitization is the phenomenon of the precipitation of:",
    answers: ["chromium carbides at grain boundaries during arc welding of stainless steels;",
    "nickel carbides at the grain boundaries during arc welding of stainless steels;",
    "molybdenum carbides at grain boundaries during arc welding of stainless steels;",
    "chromium, nickel and molybdenum carbides at the grain boundaries during arc welding of stainless steels."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"About the HAZ of a low carbon steel it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["from the point of view of loss of toughness, the most critical is the grain refining zone, as it has more dislocation accumulation;",
    "the grain growth zone is more prone to martensite formation than the grain refining zone because, in the former, the cooling rate is much higher;",
    "the grain growth zone presents higher hardenability than the intercritical one, due to large austenized grains.",
    "The maximum hardness of the HAZ depends solely on the chemical composition of the steel (hardenability)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative about steel fabrication.",
    answers: ["One of the advantages of the continuous casting process is that there is no formation of shrinkage cavities.",
    "Continuous casting is a process by which pig iron is continuously solidified into billets to be taken to a steel shop.",
    "The main advantage of continuous casting is the lower installation cost.",
    "The main disadvantage of continuous casting is lower surface quality of the product."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative about steel fabrication.",
    answers: ["The main advantage of continuous casting is the lower installation cost.",
    "Continuous casting is a process by which pig iron is continuously solidified into billets to be taken to a steel shop.",
    "In a conventional casting process, the crystals, as they grow, reject dissolved impurities into the remaining liquid, causing segregation.",
    "The main disadvantage of continuous casting is lower surface quality of the product."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Steels used for low temperature services are alloyed with:",
    answers: ["cobalt;",
    "boron;",
    "vanadium;",
    "nickel."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following properties is true for grey cast iron?",
    answers: ["Low wear resistance.",
    "Excellent damping capacity.",
    "High ductility.",
    "High melting point."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following properties is true for grey cast iron?",
    answers: ["High wear resistance.",
    "Low damping capacity.",
    "High ductility.",
    "High melting point."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following properties is true for grey cast iron?",
    answers: ["Low wear resistance.",
    "Low damping capacity.",
    "High ductility.",
    "Relatively low melting point."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Generally, Cu alloys:",
    answers: ["have lower electrical and thermal conductivity than pure copper;",
    "have higher electrical and thermal conductivity than pure copper;",
    "have much lower corrosion resistance than pure copper;",
    "they are only hot workable."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the weldability of carbon steels, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["the weldability of steels decreases with increasing carbon content due to a high tenacity of the microstructure formed;",
    "the weldability of steels decreases with increasing carbon content due to the increase in the hardenability of the material;",
    "the higher the carbon equivalent value of a steel, the better its weldability;",
    "the carbon equivalent reflects in a single number the effect of chemical composition on the various types of microstructure formed in the fused zone."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"About the ZAC it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["a final microstructure of the HAZ depends only on the cooling rate of this region;",
    "the HAZ coarse-grained region corresponds to portions of the base metal heated above its grain growth temperature, having a microstructure characterized by its high austenitic grain size;",
    "the final microstructure of the HAZ does not depend on the austenitic grain growth phenomenon;",
    "the final microstructure of the HAZ, resulting from the transformation of ferrite, depends on the contents of carbon and alloying elements in the steel."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Point out the true statement about the liquation cracking in the HAZ:",
    answers: ["It occurs between the fine grains;",
    "It only occurs in ferrous alloys with low carbon content;",
    "It always occurs near the fusion line;",
    "It only occurs in rolled steels with low ductility in the Z direction (thickness)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Considering the grain size of steels with the same chemical composition, you can say that:",
    answers: ["the smaller the grain size, the higher the yield strength, but the lower the maximum tensile strength;",
    "the larger the grain size, the higher the toughness (fewer points to crack nucleation);",
    "small grain size steels have higher strength but lower ductility;",
    "a fine granulation is obtained by full annealing heat treatment."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Among the indicated steels, which would you select for cryogenic applications?",
    answers: ["Ferritic stainless steels.",
    "High carbon ferritic-pearlitic steels.",
    "Thin thickness ferritic stainless steels (< 3 mm).",
    "Austenitic stainless steels."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Among the indicated steels, which would you select for cryogenic applications?",
    answers: ["Ferritic stainless steels.",
    "High carbon ferritic-pearlitic steels.",
    "Thin thickness ferritic stainless steels (< 3 mm).",
    "Low carbon steels with 8% Ni quenched and tempered."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"9%Ni steel is recommended for cryogenic applications because:",
    answers: ["it has high corrosion resistance;",
    "it has a very low ductile-brittle transition temperature;",
    "its yield point does not change with the reduction of temperature;",
    "its tensile strength limit does not change with a temperature reduction."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The following welding practice is used to minimize corrosion:",
    answers: ["Presence of slag adhering to the weld to prevent the formation of a corrosion pile;",
    "Whenever possible, perform welding in one pass only to avoid the formation of gaps between passes;",
    "Whenever possible, use intermittent welds instead of continuous ones (shorter welds mean less area for corrosion to appear);",
    "Complete penetration to avoid grooves in the weld root."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The following welding practice is used to minimize corrosion:",
    answers: ["Presence of slag adhering to the weld to prevent the formation of a corrosion pile;",
    "Whenever possible, perform welding in one pass only to avoid the formation of gaps between passes;",
    "Whenever possible, use intermittent welds instead of continuous ones (shorter welds mean less area for corrosion to appear);",
    "Elimination of defects that would be places of corrosive attack;"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is one of the purposes of austenitic layer buttering in hardfacing?",
    answers: ["To prevent subsequent layers from peeling off.",
    "Increased coating hardness.",
    "An increase in the total thickness of the coating (buttering + hard coating).",
    "The levelling of the substrate surface before deposition of the hard coating layer."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is one of the purposes of austenitic layer buttering in hardfacing?",
    answers: ["Prevention of cracks in the coating from propagating to the base metal.",
    "Increased coating hardness.",
    "An increase in the total thickness of the coating (buttering + hard coating).",
    "The levelling of the substrate surface before deposition of the hard coating layer."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is one of the purposes of austenitic layer buttering in hardfacing?",
    answers: ["To minimize the effects of weld pool solidification stresses (residual stresses) on the substrate.",
    "Increased coating hardness.",
    "An increase in the total thickness of the coating (buttering + hard coating).",
    "The levelling of the substrate surface before deposition of the hard coating layer."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding Titanium, its alloys and its welding, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["it is a dense and refractory metal, having typical application in structures for high temperature service;",
    "it is a very reactive metal, requiring special care for its protection (inert gases with high purity);",
    "alpha-beta and metastable beta alloys are precipitation hardenable and therefore not weldable;",
    "commercially pure titanium is relatively easy to weld and it is not embrittled by hydrogen."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"An iron alloy with 0.2% carbon was slowly cooled from 900 °C to 800 °C. What microstructure and proportion of resulting phases are at this temperature 800 °C?",
    answers: ["100% martensite with 0.2% C.",
    "50% Martensite with 0.35% C and Ferrite.",
    "Approximately 50% Ferrite and 50% Austenite with 0.2% C.",
    "50% Martensite with 0.2% C and Ferrite."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The crystalline structures of two different metallographic phases in a material may be:",
    answers: ["Segregated;",
    "Twinned;",
    "Similar;",
    "Non-coherent."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The crystalline structures of two different metallographic phases in a material may be:",
    answers: ["Segregated;",
    "Twinned;",
    "Similar;",
    "Coherent."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which factor favours stress corrosion cracking in austenitic Cr-Ni steels?",
    answers: ["Electrolyte containing chloride or fluoride.",
    "High carbon content.",
    "High compressive stresses.",
    "PWHT."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which factor favours stress corrosion cracking in austenitic Cr-Ni steels?",
    answers: ["High tensile stress or residual welding stress.",
    "High carbon content.",
    "High compressive stresses.",
    "PWHT."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The second phase of a eutectic is spherical, if:",
    answers: ["the ease of crystallisation and the surface enthalpy are high;",
    "the ease of crystallisation is high and the surface enthalpy is low;",
    "the ease of crystallisation is low and the surface enthalpy is high;",
    "the ease of crystallisation and the surface enthalpy are low."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following procedures should be used when welding fine grained steels?",
    answers: ["PWHT at 250 °C, just after welding for, at least, 48 h, to force the H2 to go out of the weld metal.",
    "PWHT at 250 °C, just after welding for 2 h, to reduce the risk of martensite formation in the weld metal.",
    "PWHT at 250 °C, just after welding for 2 h, to force the H2 to go out of the weld metal.",
    "PWHT of fine-grained steels is not recommended to prevent possible grain size growth."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is one of the reasons for the occurrence of stress corrosion cracking in stainless Cr-Ni steels without Mo?",
    answers: ["The steel might have a high carbon content.",
    "The steel might have high compressive stresses.",
    "The steel might be subjected to low service temperatures.",
    "There might be a medium containing chloride."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is one of the reasons for the occurrence of stress corrosion cracking in stainless Cr-Ni steels without Mo?",
    answers: ["The steel might have a high carbon content.",
    "The steel might have high compressive stresses.",
    "The steel might be subjected to low service temperatures.",
    "The steel might be subjected to high tensile stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding cast irons, choose the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["Ductile cast iron is obtained by adding 0.05% Mg to the grey cast iron. Magnesium precipitates spheroidal graphite instead of flakes, which increases ductility as well as mechanical strength;",
    "Malleable cast Iron is the most traditional form of cast iron. It is initially cast in the form of white cast iron and subsequently heat treated to produce nodular graphite;",
    "Cast iron is considered as a ternary alloy due to the large amount of silicon, many times greater than that of steel;",
    "When welding large pieces of cast iron without preheating, their microstructure is kept unchanged."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding dissimilar nickel alloys, it is suggested that the filler metal should be:",
    answers: ["um austenitic stainless steel;",
    "of a similar composition to the less noble alloy;",
    "of a similar composition to the more noble alloy;",
    "more noble than the noblest alloy."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What procedure is required after welding to restore corrosion resistance to nickel or nickel alloys?",
    answers: ["Post heat treatment.",
    "Pickling.",
    "Annealing.",
    "Nothing is required."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"How do the alloying elements influence the position of TTT curves?",
    answers: ["The majority of alloying elements increases the stability of super cooled austenite and thus it shifts TTT curves to the right (to higher timing).",
    "The majority of alloying elements shifts TTT curves upwards (to higher temperatures).",
    "The majority of alloying elements shifts TTT curves downwards (to lower temperatures).",
    "The majority of alloying elements accelerates the ferritic, pearlitic, bainitic and martensitic transformations, and thus it shifts TTT curves to the left."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"How does the heterogeneity of austenite influence the position of TTT curves?",
    answers: ["The heterogeneity increases the time range of diffusional ferritic, pearlitic and bainitic transformations.",
    "The heterogeneity reduces the time range for ferritic, pearlitic and bainitic transformations, as well as reduces the temperature range for martensitic and bainitic transformations.",
    "The heterogeneity shifts the TTT curves downwards (to lower temperatures).",
    "The heterogeneity accelerates the ferritic, pearlitic, bainitic and martensitic transformations, and thus it shifts TTT curves to the left."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"How does the heterogeneity of austenite influence the position of TTT curves?",
    answers: ["The heterogeneity increases the temperature range of shear transformation products (martensite and bainite).",
    "The heterogeneity reduces the time range for ferritic, pearlitic and bainitic transformations, as well as reduces the temperature range for martensitic and bainitic transformations.",
    "The heterogeneity shifts the TTT curves downwards (to lower temperatures).",
    "The heterogeneity accelerates the ferritic, pearlitic, bainitic and martensitic transformations, and thus it shifts TTT curves to the left."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Repeated cyclical rubbing between two surfaces is known as:",
    answers: ["fatigue;",
    "fretting;",
    "vibration;",
    "friction."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What may cause porosity when welding brass?",
    answers: ["Nitrogen dissolving in the weld metal.",
    "Hydrogen dissolving in the weld metal.",
    "Zinc vapourizing due to its low boiling point.",
    "Insufficient titanium in the weld metal."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"To join internally clad tube with no access for welding from the inside:",
    answers: ["filler materials compatible with the base metal (substrate) must be used;",
    "Ni base filler materials must be used;",
    "at the root, a filler metal compatible with the clad metal must be used, while the rest of the groove must be filled with the metal compatible with the base metal (substrate).",
    "In most cases it is necessary to use filler metal compatible with the clad metal over the whole thickness of the tube wall."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Carbon and nitrogen atoms diffuse sufficiently fast at moderately elevated temperatures so that they catch up to moving dislocations and immobilize them temporarily. Select the correct supporting statement.",
    answers: ["This action causes a decrease in yield strength.",
    "This action is referred to as dynamic strain aging by deformation and is accompanied by a reduction in ductility.",
    "This action is referred to as static strain aging by deformation and is accompanied by an increase in ductility.",
    "it is known as dynamic tempering and is accompanied by increased hardness."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following steels shows the least tendency to cold cracking in the HAZ:",
    answers: ["TMCP steel.",
    "Normalised steels with carbon content around 0.2%.",
    "Q&T steel.",
    "TRIP steel."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Repeated compressive load combined with abrasion is encountered in which type of wear?",
    answers: ["Metal to metal wear in motor cycle chain link against roller (in city).",
    "\"Lathe roughing operation (pair \"\"tool cutting edge - workpiece surface\"\").\"",
    "Impact wear in railway crossings.",
    "Gouging abrasion in coal feeder screws."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Repeated compressive load combined with abrasion is encountered in which type of wear?",
    answers: ["Metal to metal wear in motor cycle chain link against roller (in city).",
    "\"Lathe roughing operation (pair \"\"tool cutting edge - workpiece surface\"\").\"",
    "High stress abrasion in bull dozer blades",
    "Gouging abrasion in coal feeder screws."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Repeated compressive load combined with abrasion is encountered in which type of wear?",
    answers: ["Metal to metal wear in motor cycle chain link against roller (in city).",
    "\"Lathe roughing operation (pair \"\"tool cutting edge - workpiece surface\"\").\"",
    "\"Metal to metal wear in motor cycle chain link against roller (rally \"\"Dakar\"\").\"",
    "Gouging abrasion in coal feeder screws."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following statements is correct when considering the weldability of austenitic stainless steels for high temperature services?",
    answers: ["There is sensitivity to overheating.",
    "There is a tendency to cold cracking.",
    "There is a tendency to cracking due to the formation of martensite.",
    "Loss of impact energy is likely."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following statements is correct when considering the weldability of austenitic stainless steels?",
    answers: ["Increased grain growth in the heat affected zone.",
    "There is a tendency to cold cracking.",
    "There is a tendency to cracking due to the formation of martensite.",
    "There is a tendency to hot cracking."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which statement regarding aluminium is correct?",
    answers: ["Its resistance to low temperatures is comparable to that of austenitic stainless steel because the lattice structure is the same FCC.",
    "Its creep resistance is comparable to that of austenitic stainless steel because the lattice structure is the same FCC.",
    "Its corrosion resistance is comparable to that of austenitic stainless steel because the lattice structure is also FCC.",
    "Its resistance to low temperatures is comparable to that of austenitic stainless steel because the lattice structure is also BCC."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"For welding of austenitic-ferritic duplex stainless steels, what is the cause of the high ferrite content in the heat affected zone of a welded joint?",
    answers: ["Use of filler material containing Nickel.",
    "High cooling rate.",
    "Low cooling rate.",
    "Preheating temperature is too high."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What measures reduce possibility of hot cracking of heat-resistant nickel alloys in welding?",
    answers: ["Preheating.",
    "Post heating.",
    "Limitation of cross-section area for each run.",
    "Welding with low heat input."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is an advantage of using a duplex stainless steel over an austenitic or a ferritic grade stainless steel?",
    answers: ["Duplex stainless steel shows excellent stress corrosion cracking (SCC) resistance, thanks to its ferritic properties.",
    "Less embrittlement risks.",
    "Improved high temperature performance.",
    "Control of welding parameters is less rigorous."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is an advantage of using a duplex stainless steel over an austenitic or a ferritic grade stainless steel?",
    answers: ["Duplex stainless steel is about twice as strong as regular austenitic or ferritic stainless steels.",
    "Less embrittlement risks.",
    "Improved high temperature performance.",
    "Control of welding parameters is less rigorous."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is an advantage of using a duplex stainless steel over an austenitic or a ferritic grade stainless steel?",
    answers: ["Due to its increased yield strength, it may be possible to reduce its section thickness for some applications.",
    "Less embrittlement risks.",
    "Improved high temperature performance.",
    "Control of welding parameters is less rigorous."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is an advantage of using a duplex stainless steel over an austenitic or a ferritic grade stainless steel?",
    answers: ["Duplex stainless steels have significantly better toughness and ductility than ferritic steel.",
    "Less embrittlement risks.",
    "Improved high temperature performance.",
    "Control of welding parameters is less rigorous."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"An increased content of alloying elements in copper alloys ...",
    answers: ["always improves the weldability, as it reduces thermal conductivity;",
    "always worsens the weldability, as it increases brittleness at high temperature;",
    "can improve or worsen the weldability depending on the content of each alloy element;",
    "does not significantly influence the weldability of copper alloys, as they are all characterized by poor weldability."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Choose the correct alternative regarding the welding of dissimilar materials:",
    answers: ["The Schaeffler diagram is useful for predicting the structure resulting from the welding of dissimilar materials only when there is a filler metal;",
    "The use of different filler metals for buttering and filling in dissimilar joints allows avoiding brittle welds;",
    "The two axes of the Schaeffler diagram are chrome and nickel;",
    "The temperature control of a joint of austenitic stainless steel x carbon steel is due to the attempt to avoid the sensitization of carbon steel."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding dissimilar materials, the mechanical resistance of the weld metal should be, as a general rule:",
    answers: ["compatible with that of the least resistant member of the joint;",
    "compatible with that of the most resistant member of the joint;",
    "equal to the average value of this parameter for the two members of the joint;",
    "slightly lower than the value of this parameter for the most resistant member of the joint to avoid sudden changes in the mechanical properties within the joint."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding dissimilar materials, the corrosion and oxidation resistance of the weld metal should be, as a general rule:",
    answers: ["equal or greater of the corrosion resistance of the less resistant base metal;",
    "compatible with that of the most resistant member of the joint;",
    "equal to the average resistance for the two members of the joint;",
    "slightly lower than the value of this parameter for the most resistant member of the joint to avoid creating a galvanic pile."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding fragile dissimilar materials, the weld metal must be:",
    answers: ["ductile and tenacious (example: cast iron + nickel);",
    "ductile on the side of the fragile component and hard on the soft component;",
    "always of austenitic stainless steel;",
    "also fragile to avoid abrupt changes in mechanical properties within the joint."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which difficulty is encountered in welding of ferritic stainless steels?",
    answers: ["Formation an as-cast structure in the weld.",
    "Increased grain growth in the heat affected zone.",
    "There is a tendency to hot cracking.",
    "There is a tendency to cracking due to the formation of martensite."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"About pressure vessels, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["the pressure vessel works under a pressure higher or lower than atmospheric pressure;",
    "in the hydrostatic test, the pressure vessels are subjected to a slightly lower pressure than the working pressure, introducing water;",
    "in the hydrostatic test, the pressure vessels are subjected to a pressure higher than the working pressure, introducing compressed air;",
    "there is no way to apply the hydrostatic test to boilers, due to the flames."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About pressure vessels, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["the pressure vessel is that one that works under a pressure higher than atmospheric pressure;",
    "in the hydrostatic test, the pressure vessels are subjected to a slightly lower pressure than the working pressure, introducing water;",
    "in the hydrostatic test, the pressure vessels are subjected to a pressure higher than the working pressure, introducing water;",
    "there is no way to apply the hydrostatic test to boilers, due to the flames."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the stress concentration in workpieces, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["The geometric coefficient of stress concentration (Stress Concentration Factor) takes into account the sensitivity of the material to the notch;",
    "In general, higher strength steels are less sensitive to notch than more ductile steels;",
    "The fatigue stress concentration coefficient is a function of the geometry of the workpiece and of the notch, as well as of the material susceptibility.",
    "A high reinforcement of the welded joint does not influence fatigue failure as it is not characterized as a notch."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The peening technique aims, in terms of structure behaviour under cyclic stresses, to:",
    answers: ["increase the tensile strength of the weld metal;",
    "remove weld surface defects in order to increase fatigue strength of the weld metal;",
    "increase weld fatigue strength by inducing surface compressive stresses;",
    "increase the fatigue strength of the weld by inducing the formation of ductile microconstituents on the surface."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It has a decisive influence on the fatigue strength of a welded structure:",
    answers: ["number of cycles;",
    "frequency of loading;",
    "surface roughness of the material;",
    "compressive residual stresses induced by welding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It has a decisive influence on the fatigue strength of a welded structure:",
    answers: ["number of cycles;",
    "frequency of loading;",
    "residual tensile stresses induced by welding;",
    "compressive residual stresses induced by welding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It has a decisive influence on the fatigue strength of a welded structure:",
    answers: ["number of cycles;",
    "frequency of loading;",
    "a misalignment of the neutral fibres between two components of welded joint;",
    "compressive residual stresses induced by welding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the safety factor, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The safety factor is the ratio between the ultimate stress (maximum stress) of the material and the allowable stress;",
    "The safety factor is the ratio between the allowable stress and the ultimate stress (maximum stress) of the material;",
    "Improvements in the quality of materials and an effective control of the works execution allow for an increase in the safety factor;",
    "The safety factor depends on the quality of the material and is independent of the type of loading."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the safety factor, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The choice of a low safety factor can lead the structure to the possibility of failure;",
    "The safety factor is the ratio between the allowable stress and the ultimate stress (maximum stress) of the material;",
    "Improvements in the quality of materials and an effective control of the works execution allow for an increase in the safety factor;",
    "The safety factor depends on the quality of the material and is independent of the type of loading."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the safety factor, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["Choosing a high safety factor can lead to an uneconomical design;",
    "The safety factor is the ratio between the allowable stress and the ultimate stress (maximum stress) of the material;",
    "Improvements in the quality of materials and an effective control of the works execution allow for an increase in the safety factor;",
    "The safety factor depends on the quality of the material and is independent of the type of loading."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the safety factor, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["A very well-done design can admit a relatively low safety factor;",
    "The safety factor is the ratio between the allowable stress and the ultimate stress (maximum stress) of the material;",
    "Improvements in the quality of materials and an effective control of the works execution allow for an increase in the safety factor;",
    "The safety factor depends on the quality of the material and is independent of the type of loading."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The abbreviation of the CTOD test name stands for:",
    answers: ["Crack Tenacity (testing) by Offset Distance;",
    "Crack Tip Opening Displacement testing;",
    "Crack Transmission by Overload and Deformation;",
    "Control of Toughness by Offset Distance."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About high strength steels it can be said that they:",
    answers: ["ensure a reduction in brittle fracture sensitivity;",
    "ensure better quality welds thanks to their better weldability;",
    "are characterized by a high resistance to high cycle fatigue;",
    "are characterized by a low resistance to high cycle fatigue."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these theories of strength may be applied when calculating strength calculations of steel structures?",
    answers: ["Theory of maximum service life.",
    "Theory of maximum shear (tangential) stress.",
    "Maximum loading theory.",
    "Acceptable deformation theory."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these theories of strength may be applied when calculating strength calculations of steel structures?",
    answers: ["Theory of maximum service life.",
    "Theory of maximum distortion energy.",
    "Maximum loading theory.",
    "Acceptable deformation theory."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The heating and cooling cycles suffered by metal structures can cause:",
    answers: ["creep failures;",
    "reduction of fracture toughness;",
    "hydrogen cracking;",
    "thermal fatigue failure."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"How would it be possible to increase the fatigue strength of aluminium alloy butt joints?",
    answers: ["Brushing the aluminium oxide layer.",
    "Applying peening.",
    "Welding with backing.",
    "\"Using \"\"V\"\" joint edge preparation instead of \"\"U\"\" preparation.\""],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"How would it be possible to increase the fatigue strength of aluminium alloy butt joints?",
    answers: ["Brushing the aluminium oxide layer.",
    "Remelting the weld toe by the TIG process (TIG-dressing).",
    "Welding with backing.",
    "\"Using \"\"V\"\" joint edge preparation instead of \"\"U\"\" preparation.\""],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"A compressed gas, is a gas or mixture of gases in a closed container at a pressure … (under a temperature of 21 deg. C):",
    answers: ["higher than 200 kPa;",
    "higher than 275 kPa;",
    "higher than 300 kPa;",
    "higher than 315 kPa."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"About the equilibrium of a rigid body, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["A rigid body will be in equilibrium if the external forces acting on it are equal to the internal forces;",
    "The equilibrium condition of a rigid body also applies to deformable structures, but until a deformation occurs;",
    "A rigid body is in equilibrium when the sum of the external forces acting on it is equal to zero and the sum of the moments is also equal to zero;",
    "The structure is considered to be statically indeterminate if it is subjected to the action of more than one force."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the application of rebars (reinforcing steel bars) in civil construction, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["According to ISO 17660, the recommended welding processes for welding rebars are: 111, 135, 21 and 441;",
    "As per ISO 17660, fillet welds are not applicable to rebars;",
    "MIG/MAG welding cannot be used to weld rebars in the field, as this process cannot be carried out in the presence of winds.",
    "The ribs prevent the rebar from rotating within the concrete. In this way, the rebar acts together with the structure when subjected to load."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the welding reinforcing bars (rebars), it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["They are weldable by most processes, but there are rebars that are not recommended for welding;",
    "They should not be welded, unless with high preheating, to avoid cold cracking;",
    "Electric resistance welding processes should be avoided, as the applied pressure creates overheating in the contact area with the electrode;",
    "Fillet welds are not applicable to rebars."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the welding reinforcing bars (rebars), it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["Despite having a relatively high carbon equivalent (between 0.35 and 0.45), they do not require preheating;",
    "They should not be welded, unless with high preheating, to avoid cold cracking;",
    "Electric resistance welding processes should be avoided, as the applied pressure creates overheating in the contact area with the electrode;",
    "Fillet welds are not applicable to rebars."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding radiographic exposure techniques:",
    answers: ["The Panoramic Exposure technique provides high productivity and quickness of examinations of circular welded joints that have no an internal access;",
    "The Single Wall Single Image (SWSI) technique is considered the main technique used in radiographic inspection and the easiest to be interpreted;",
    "The Double Wall Single Image (DWSI) method is used in inspections of welded joints of pipes that have an internal access;",
    "The Double Wall Double Image (DWDI) method is generally used for inspection of welded joints in large diameter pipelines."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding radiographic exposure techniques:",
    answers: ["The Double Wall Double Image (DWDI) technique is generally used for inspection of welded joints in large diameter pipelines;",
    "The Panoramic Exposure technique provides high productivity and quickness of examinations of circular welded joints that have an internal access;",
    "The Double Wall Single Image (DWSI) method is used in inspections of welded joints of pipes that have an internal access;",
    "The Single Wall Single Image (SWSI) method is the least used in radiographic inspection due to a difficult interpretation."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding radiographic exposure techniques:",
    answers: ["The Panoramic Exposure technique provides high productivity and quickness of examinations of circular welded joints that have no an internal access;",
    "The Double Wall Single Image (DWSI) technique is used in inspections of welded joints of pipes that do not have internal access;",
    "The Double Wall Double Image (DWDI) method is generally used for inspection of welded joints in large diameter pipelines.",
    "The Single Wall Single Image (SWSI) method is the least used in radiographic inspection due to a difficult interpretation"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding radiographic exposure techniques:",
    answers: ["The Panoramic Exposure technique provides high productivity and quickness of examinations of circular welded joints that have no an internal access;",
    "The Double Wall Double Image (DWDI) technique is generally used only on pipes less than 75-80 mm in diameter;",
    "The Double Wall Single Image (DWSI) method is used in inspections of welded joints of pipes that have an internal access;",
    "The Single Wall Single Image (SWSI) method is the least used in radiographic inspection due to a difficult interpretation"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the cost of electric power for 1-hour welding by the GMAW process in automatic mode (non-stop), with the following parameters: 20 V, 200 A, power source efficiency - 0.8, electric power costs - USD 0.20 kWh?",
    answers: ["USD 1.00.",
    "USD 2.00.",
    "USD 3.00.",
    "USD 4.00."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The ISO 9001 standard - Quality Management Systems - Requirements:",
    answers: ["is identical to the ISO 3834 standard - Quality requirements for fusion welding of metallic materials;",
    "has nothing to do with the Quality System presented by the ISO 3834;",
    "is the basis of the ISO 3034-1 standard in terms of determining the quality requirements applicable to the welding process;",
    "serves as the basis for the ISO 14731 standard – Welding coordination - Tasks and responsibilities."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of these subjects is NOT addressed in ISO 3834 - \"\"Quality requirements for fusion welding of metallic materials\"\"?\"",
    answers: ["Storage and handling of welding consumables. ",
    "Post-weld heat treatment.",
    "Sub-contracting.",
    "Welding costs."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of these subjects is NOT addressed in ISO 3834 - \"\"Quality requirements for fusion welding of metallic materials\"\"?\"",
    answers: ["Storage of parent material.",
    "Inspection and testing.",
    "Productivity.",
    "Welders and welding operators."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of these subjects is NOT addressed in ISO 3834 - \"\"Quality requirements for fusion welding of metallic materials\"\"?\"",
    answers: ["Welding co-ordination personnel.",
    "Metal transfer mode.",
    "Equipment maintenance.",
    "Production planning."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of these subjects is NOT addressed in ISO 3834 - \"\"Quality requirements for fusion welding of metallic materials\"\"?\"",
    answers: ["Preheating.",
    "WPSs.",
    "Non-conformance and corrective actions.",
    "Calibration or validation of measuring, inspection and testing equipment."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of these subjects is NOT addressed in ISO 3834 - \"\"Quality requirements for fusion welding of metallic materials\"\"?\"",
    answers: ["Inspection and testing personnel.",
    "Traceability.",
    "Qualification of the welding procedures.",
    "Hygiene and safety."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"In which of the options below are the ISO 3834 Parts arranged in increasing order of the quality requirements?",
    answers: ["Part 1, Part 2 and Part 3.",
    "Part 3, Part 2 and Part 1.",
    "Part 2, Part 3 and Part 4.",
    "Part 4, Part 3 and Part 2."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"According to the ISO 14731 - \"\"Welding coordination - Tasks and responsibilities\"\", the company, when subcontracting the Welding Coordination activity,:\"",
    answers: ["delegates full responsibility to the third party;",
    "can define that the responsibility is shared with the subcontractor;",
    "remains responsible for the compliance to that standard;",
    "shall also appoint an in-house welding coordinator, even at the basic level of competence."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The ISO 3834 standard requires:",
    answers: ["that the critical analysis of the customer's requirements is carried out only if required by the contract;",
    "that the customer's requirements review to be done only for Comprehensive Quality Requirements;",
    "that customer's requirements review to be done only for Comprehensive and Standard Quality Requirements;",
    "that all quality requirements levels perform a critical analysis of customer's requirements."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The ISO 3834 standard requires:",
    answers: ["that non-destructive inspections to be carried out for all critical joints;",
    "that non-destructive inspections to be carried out only for Comprehensive Quality Requirements;",
    "that non-destructive inspections to be carried out only for Comprehensive and Standard Quality Requirements;",
    "that non-destructive inspections to be carried out for all quality requirements levels."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The ISO 3834 standard requires:",
    answers: ["that all welders and welding operators to be well trained.",
    "that welders and welding operators to be qualified only for Comprehensive Quality Requirements;",
    "that welders and welding operators to be qualified only for Comprehensive and Standard Quality Requirements;",
    "that all welders and welding operators to be qualified."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"A non-essential variable is ...",
    answers: ["a welding condition addressed in the WPS but not requiring qualification;",
    "a welding condition that is not addressed in the WPS;",
    "a welding condition that requires qualification if being addressed in the WPS;",
    "a parameter that does not influence welding process (e.g., welding costs, energy consumption, …)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Examples of essential variables are (according to ISO 15614-1):",
    answers: ["Welding process, Metal transfer mode, Shielding gas flow rate;",
    "Parent material thickness, Diameter (for pipes), Method of back gouging;",
    "Welding position, Type of joint/weld, Heat input;",
    "Parent material thickness, Interpass Temperature, Shielding gas flow rate."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Examples of essential variables are (according to ISO 15614-1):",
    answers: ["Preheat temperature, Shielding gas type, Welding power source output characteristic type;",
    "Parent material thickness, Diameter (for pipes), Shield gas nozzle size;",
    "Welding process, Parent material type, Welding position;",
    "Type of Current and Polarity, Parent material thickness, Shielding gas flow rate."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the most important mechanical property of the weld metal for a repair weld on a structure working at ambient temperature?",
    answers: ["High tensile strength.",
    "High elongation.",
    "\"Low \"\"ductile - brittle\"\" transition temperature.\"",
    "High yield strength."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is considered as one of the objectives of an audit of the Quality Assurance and Quality Control Systems:",
    answers: ["Check the financial health of the company;",
    "Prepare the organization for certification;",
    "Collect information for the development of the Inspection and Test Plan;",
    "Verify that NDT inspection tests are performed on welded joints when customers start complaining about welding quality."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is considered as one of the objectives of an audit of the Quality Assurance and Quality Control Systems:",
    answers: ["Check the financial health of the company;",
    "Check if the established procedures are relevant and if they are applied;",
    "Collect information for the development of the Inspection and Test Plan;",
    "Verify that NDT inspection tests are performed on welded joints when customers start complaining about welding quality."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is considered as one of the objectives of an audit of the Quality Assurance and Quality Control Systems:",
    answers: ["Check the financial health of the company;",
    "Periodic verification of compliance with work instructions, inspection program, work plans and targets;",
    "Collect information for the development of the Inspection and Test Plan;",
    "Verify that NDT inspection tests are performed on welded joints when customers start complaining about welding quality."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is considered as one of the objectives of an audit of the Quality Assurance and Quality Control Systems:",
    answers: ["Check the financial health of the company;",
    "So that the company's top management is aware that the objectives are fully achieved;",
    "Collect information for the development of the Inspection and Test Plan;",
    "Verify that NDT inspection tests are performed on welded joints when customers start complaining about welding quality."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Blind Hole Drilling Technique for residual stress measurement, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["It is a destructive method and can only be performed on laboratory samples;",
    "It can measure residual stresses across the entire thickness of the sheet (mapping), even in thick plate metal;",
    "The hole is drilled before welding to record its parameters which will serve as references for the hole parameters after welding;",
    "Although intrusive, it is a relatively low-cost and practical method."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Blind Hole Drilling Technique for residual stress measurement, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["It is a destructive method and can only be performed on laboratory samples;",
    "It can measure residual stresses across the entire thickness of the sheet (mapping), even in thick plate metal;",
    "The hole is drilled before welding to record its parameters which will serve as references for the hole parameters after welding;",
    "The hole is made after welding, not before."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Blind Hole Drilling Technique for residual stress measurement, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["It is a destructive method and can only be performed on laboratory samples;",
    "It can measure residual stresses across the entire thickness of the sheet (mapping), even in thick plate metal;",
    "The hole is drilled before welding to record its parameters which will serve as references for the hole parameters after welding;",
    "The blind hole method determines the residual stress near the surface of a linear elastic isotropic material."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Blind Hole Drilling Technique for residual stress measurement, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["It is a destructive method and can only be performed on laboratory samples;",
    "It can measure residual stresses across the entire thickness of the sheet (mapping), even in thick plate metal;",
    "The hole is drilled before welding to record its parameters which will serve as references for the hole parameters after welding;",
    "This method has advantages such as portability and low-cost instrumentation."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Blind Hole Drilling Technique for residual stress measurement, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["It is a destructive method and can only be performed on laboratory samples;",
    "It can measure residual stresses across the entire thickness of the sheet (mapping), even in thick plate metal;",
    "The hole is drilled before welding to record its parameters which will serve as references for the hole parameters after welding;",
    "One of the limitations of this method is that it is only applicable in structures where the drilled hole does not affect its operation."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Blind Hole Drilling Technique for residual stress measurement, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["It is a destructive method and can only be performed on laboratory samples;",
    "It can measure residual stresses across the entire thickness of the sheet (mapping), even in thick plate metal;",
    "The hole is drilled before welding to record its parameters which will serve as references for the hole parameters after welding;",
    "The method is indifferent whether the stresses are caused by external loading or are residual stresses."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Blind Hole Drilling Technique for residual stress measurement, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["It is a destructive method and can only be performed on laboratory samples;",
    "It can measure residual stresses across the entire thickness of the sheet (mapping), even in thick plate metal;",
    "The hole is drilled before welding to record its parameters which will serve as references for the hole parameters after welding;",
    "The main sources of errors can be: drilling technique, hole geometry, environmental conditions, among others."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Blind Hole Drilling Technique for residual stress measurement, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["It is a destructive method and can only be performed on laboratory samples;",
    "It can measure residual stresses across the entire thickness of the sheet (mapping), even in thick plate metal;",
    "The hole is drilled before welding to record its parameters which will serve as references for the hole parameters after welding;",
    "It is a semi-destructive technique, as the damage caused is very localized, not compromising the full functioning of the measured workpiece."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Blind Hole Drilling Technique for residual stress measurement, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["It is a destructive method and can only be performed on laboratory samples;",
    "It can measure residual stresses across the entire thickness of the sheet (mapping), even in thick plate metal;",
    "The hole is drilled before welding to record its parameters which will serve as references for the hole parameters after welding;",
    "It is a semi-destructive technique, for hole diameters around 1.0 - 1.6 mm with a depth of 0.5 - 1.0 mm, becoming a destructive technique for larger holes and thin sheets."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"}
];